<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>pages tagged usability</title>
<link href="http://magnetic-babysitter.local/tag/usability/"/>
<link href="http://magnetic-babysitter.local/tag/usability/index.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<author>

<name>rainskiwikit.com</name>

</author>




<id>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/tag/usability/</id>

<subtitle type="html">rainskiwikit.com</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://ikiwiki.info/">ikiwiki</generator>
<updated>2013-08-18T04:39:11Z</updated>
<entry>
	<title>Laptop bag 4.0, backlogs, and story form</title>

	<id>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/622/laptop-bag-40-backlogs-and-story-form/</id>

	<link href="http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/622/laptop-bag-40-backlogs-and-story-form/"/>






	<category term="agile" />

	<category term="business" />

	<category term="effectiveness" />

	<category term="flying" />

	<category term="geek" />

	<category term="product management" />

	<category term="reviews" />

	<category term="travel" />

	<category term="usability" />


	<updated>2013-08-18T04:39:11Z</updated>
	<published>2013-08-18T04:34:14Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;Somewhere out there is a laptop bag just waiting for me to find it.  But first, I have to spec it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randsinrepose.com/&quot;&gt;Rands&lt;/a&gt;, I recently got &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randsinrepose.com/archives/2011/12/04/a_bag_of_holding.html&quot;&gt;laptop bag religion&lt;/a&gt; and I spent an excessive amount of time cogitating about features, price, tradeoffs, where to buy, and features again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got serious about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t yet found the bag, but in the meantime, I&amp;#39;ve written this blog post, because it provided the excuse I needed to really &lt;del&gt;go batshit insane&lt;/del&gt; do a thorough job of my analysis.  Not only does this post include a detailed list of requirements for my perfect laptop bag, but it also includes a glance into what I do in my life as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/586/what-i-do&quot;&gt;Product Manager&lt;/a&gt;.  Hopefully one or the other of those is interesting enough to keep your attention &lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/tag/usability/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/tag/usability/../../blog/622/laptop-bag-40-backlogs-and-story-form/#more&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	</content>



</entry>
<entry>
	<title>Apple vs. Dell/Microsoft</title>

	<id>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft/</id>

	<link href="http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft/"/>






	<category term="apple" />

	<category term="reviews" />

	<category term="usability" />


	<updated>2013-06-03T00:02:15Z</updated>
	<published>2013-06-03T00:02:15Z</published>

	<content type="html" xml:lang="en">
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;27 July 2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a MacBook Air that I used as my work (consulting) computer for 18
months or so. Then my new job gave me a Dell laptop that &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/115702184162942442429/posts/HrRj16gEYJa&quot;&gt;feels seriously
inferior&lt;/a&gt;, but as with all things Windows/Dell, it is sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yesterday I did something I&#39;ve done hundreds of times before with my Air,
but never before with my Dell: I closed the lid at the end of the day without
shutting things down first, stuffed it in my bag, and went home. (I was in a
hurry.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Air, that reliably sleeps the laptop, and I can always trust that
everything will be exactly as I left it when I reopen the lid, and the battery
won&#39;t have drained at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew not to trust the same thing on Windows, but I was in a hurry so I
decided to risk it, and maybe if it turned out well I&#39;d adjust my opinion
about Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did I see when I opened it this morning? A boot-time message telling
me that the laptop had shut itself down because it was overheating, which
usually happens because it is in a tightly enclosed space with the fan vents
blocked. Like, say, a laptop bag. And by &quot;shut itself down&quot; they mean &quot;hard
power off, no saving your work&quot;. And they mean that they waited until the
battery was half drained to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I checked and I do have the laptop set to sleep when I close the lid. So
it should have just slept, and it shouldn&#39;t have been generating heat
(although I&#39;m not certain if the Windows sleep really does go that far), so it
shouldn&#39;t have had this problem. But it did. I&#39;m guessing the culprit is
Outlook, which often prevents rebooting because of third-party integrations
that aren&#39;t very well-done, so maybe it also prevented sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then of course, the culprit is Windows for actually listening to Outlook
and not putting the laptop to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then Dell is really the savior here; faced with Windows not sleeping when
it was supposed to, Dell&#39;s choice was either to let the laptop overheat (and
break permanently), or build a feature to shut it off when it begins to. So,
thanks, Dell!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than that, thanks to Apple for making devices where I just don&#39;t have
to worry about crap like this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Comments&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft#c000947&quot;&gt;172 days ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mattmc3.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;mattmc3&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, right? The thought of ever going back just doesn&#39;t cross my mind. But,
as a counter-point, I did have the exact opposite problem today in fact. I
wanted my laptop to stay on while I updated the maps on my Garmin and the Mac
insisted it follow the energy settings which meant that the Garmin was 1/2
updated when the laptop force ejected it as part of its sleep routine. The
default behavior is certainly what you want 99% of the time, but for that 1% I
wish there was an easy way to say &quot;delay sleep&quot; for x minutes because I know
what I&#39;m doing and after that return to my prior settings automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft#c000948&quot;&gt;172 days ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com&quot;&gt;Nathan Arthur&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://semaja2.net/insomniaxinfo&quot;&gt;InsomniaX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/macosx-nosleep-extension/&quot;&gt;NoSleep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And &lt;a href=&quot;http://lightheadsw.com/caffeine/&quot;&gt;Caffeine&lt;/a&gt; for non-lid-closed cases)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/tag/usability/../../smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	</content>



</entry>

</feed>
