<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<channel>
<title>rainskiwikit.com</title>
<link>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/index.html</link>
<description>rainskiwikit.com</description>
<item>

	<title>This year for Lent...</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/630/this-year-for-lent.html</guid>

	<link>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/630/this-year-for-lent.html</link>


	<category>lent</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 22:30:08 -0400</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-03T02:30:08Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;12 February 2013&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I&amp;#8217;ll be giving up staying up late. (Starting tomorrow, the first day of
Lent.) For me, that means I&amp;#8217;ll be in bed by 11pm every night of Lent. This
year will be a &lt;em&gt;serious&lt;/em&gt; test of my self-discipline &lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confused about why I&amp;#8217;m doing this? See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/tag/lent/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>10 Questions a Pro-Choice Candidate Is Never Asked by the Media</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/629/10-questions-a-pro-choice-candidate-is-never-asked-by-the-media.html</guid>

	<link>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/629/10-questions-a-pro-choice-candidate-is-never-asked-by-the-media.html</link>


	<category>abortion</category>

	<category>economics</category>

	<category>links</category>

	<category>religion</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 20:02:15 -0400</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-03T00:02:15Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;25 October 2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mattmc3.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;My friend&lt;/a&gt; has &lt;a href=&quot;http://mattmc3.tumblr.com/post/7080355507/speaking-about-the-unspeakable-on-behalf-of-the-unheard&quot;&gt;again&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mattmc3.tumblr.com/post/34302314350/10-questions-a-pro-choice-candidate-is-never-asked-by&quot;&gt;posted a link&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://thegospelcoalition.org/blogs/trevinwax/2012/10/24/10-questions-a-pro-choice-candidate-is-never-asked-by-the-media/&quot;&gt;an article about
abortion&lt;/a&gt;. I find myself unable to avoid addressing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article poses 10 questions. Theoretically the article is complaining about
how the media doesn&amp;#8217;t ever ask pro-choice candidates about those questions,
but other than the paragraph at the top mentioning that complaint, the rest is
just the list of 10 questions. I don&amp;#8217;t much care whether the media asks those
questions (see: some future blog post), so I&amp;#8217;m not going to worry about
addressing that issue. Instead, I&amp;#8217;ll just reply with my own opinions about the
10 questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll need to have read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/610/on-abortion&quot;&gt;my previous post giving an overview of my
opinions&lt;/a&gt; if you want to understand my answers. I&amp;#8217;m not going to restate
those opinions here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. You say you support a woman’s right to make her own reproductive choices in regards to abortion and contraception. Are there any restrictions you would approve of?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes: no abortions after the first trimester unless the pregnancy puts the
mother&amp;#8217;s life at an unusually-high level of risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. In 2010, The Economist featured a cover story on “the war on girls” and the growth of “gendercide” in the world – abortion based solely on the sex of the baby. Does this phenomenon pose a problem for you or do you believe in the absolute right of a woman to terminate a pregnancy because the unborn fetus is female?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first trimester, she doesn&amp;#8217;t have to justify the abortion to me or
anybody else. I find that practice reprehensible, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean I have
the right to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. In many states, a teenager can have an abortion without her parents’ consent or knowledge but cannot get an aspirin from the school nurse without parental authorization. Do you support any restrictions or parental notification regarding abortion access for minors?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I generally believe that once you&amp;#8217;re pregnant, you&amp;#8217;re an adult, whether you&amp;#8217;re
ready to be or not. Under that postulate, then abortion should not require
parental consent or notification. I am nearly on the fence about
&amp;#8220;notification&amp;#8221; but I figure if the teenager&amp;#8217;s relationship with the parents is
good, then the parents will find out, and if it&amp;#8217;s bad, then we (society)
shouldn&amp;#8217;t put the teenager at more risk by harming that relationship even
more. Sometimes the outcome won&amp;#8217;t fall in a positive way, but that&amp;#8217;s also true
if we always notify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of aspirin, schools shouldn&amp;#8217;t give drugs to children without
authorization. If that child has been declared an adult, then they shouldn&amp;#8217;t
need authorization. If they&amp;#8217;ve been declared an adult because they were
pregnant… well, that requires parental notification, which violates the
earlier rule. It should be up to the teenager whether to make their adulthood
formal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4. If you do not believe that human life begins at conception, when do you believe it begins? At what stage of development should an unborn child have human rights?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human life begins at conception; that&amp;#8217;s a biological fact. Self-awareness does
not begin until much later, and I&amp;#8217;m sure it&amp;#8217;s after the first trimester. (Or
at least sure enough that I&amp;#8217;m willing to work with it as a safe assumption.)
So the fetus should not have human rights during the first trimester, and then
to be on the safe side, it should have the right to not be arbitrarily
murdered after that. I didn&amp;#8217;t say it should have &amp;#8220;human rights&amp;#8221; - those are
fuzzy and generally considered in terms of adults. If you look at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.un.org/en/documents/udhr/index.shtml&quot;&gt;UN
declaration of human rights&lt;/a&gt;, many of them are violated by constraints
imposed by nature (i.e. the placenta) so long as the fetus is still in the
womb, because they don&amp;#8217;t really consider the rights of children at all, let
alone fetuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;5. Currently, when genetic testing reveals an unborn child has Down Syndrome, most women choose to abort. How do you answer the charge that this phenomenon resembles the “eugenics” movement a century ago – the slow, but deliberate “weeding out” of those our society would deem “unfit” to live?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That the charge is dumb. The eugenics movement was a societally-promoted
effort to improve the race, at the level of the entire race. Women choosing to
abort a child with Down Syndrome is a personal choice based on weighing many,
many issues specific to their immediate life and situation. The fact that they
both use the same mechanism for achieving their ends does not make them the
same, just like me driving a car to work does not make me the same as someone
who drives a car into another person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;6. Do you believe an employer should be forced to violate his or her religious conscience by providing access to abortifacient drugs and contraception to employees?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I don&amp;#8217;t believe an employer should force his or her
religious conscience on employees by only providing medical insurance coverage
that the employer finds tasteful. Why should we allow employers to force their
religious ideas on employees, but not allow employees to force their religious
ideas on employers? The fact is, providing health insurance that lets the
employees make their own choice is the only way to respect the rights of each
party; the employers who care about this are just trying to say that their
rights supersede their employees&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But practically, I don&amp;#8217;t see a reason to stop them, either; the employees
aren&amp;#8217;t forced to work there. It&amp;#8217;s also dumb that we have employer-sponsored
healthcare in the first place, but that problem will take many years to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;7. Alveda King, niece of Martin Luther King, Jr. has said that “abortion is the white supremacist’s best friend,” pointing to the fact that Black and Latinos represent 25% of our population but account for 59% of all abortions.  How do you respond to the charge that the majority of abortion clinics are found in inner-city areas with large numbers of minorities?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Correlation does not imply causation, nor does it imply intent or conspiracy.
Take a logic or statistics class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;8. You describe abortion as a “tragic choice.” If abortion is not morally objectionable, then why is it tragic? Does this mean there is something about abortion that is different than other standard surgical procedures?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t actually describe it that way. I think it&amp;#8217;s often &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the worst
choice; that&amp;#8217;s what &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freakonomics.com/&quot;&gt;the economists tell us&lt;/a&gt;, anyway. So in that sense, if
abortion is the lesser of two evils, then I can&amp;#8217;t see it as wholly tragic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But… as &amp;#8220;the lesser evil&amp;#8221; it is still evil. But that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean that the
tragedy is the abortion itself; the tragedy is all the things that led to a
point where the abortion is the better option. In such a situation, it might
actually be more tragic to deliver the baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question as written also implies that no other surgical procedures are
tragic. Is removing a limb not tragic? Again, if removing the limb saves a
life, then it doesn&amp;#8217;t seem wholly tragic. The tragedy was really at whatever
event caused it to be necessary, and it would be further tragedy to leave the
limb in place and have the patient die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;9. Do you believe abortion should be legal once the unborn fetus is viable – able to survive outside the womb?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, no. The fetus isn&amp;#8217;t viable until after the first trimester, under
today&amp;#8217;s medical science. Over time, that will probably change, though - maybe
we&amp;#8217;ll eventually be able to get a baby entirely without a human mother
directly involved. In such a case, the overriding issue is still self-
awareness, and abortion should be legal so long as we&amp;#8217;re sure the fetus isn&amp;#8217;t
self-aware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;10. If a pregnant woman and her unborn child are murdered, do you believe the criminal should face two counts of murder and serve a harsher sentence?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first trimester, no. After… well, if they knew they were killing
the fetus, then yes. But if they didn&amp;#8217;t, then the second count shouldn&amp;#8217;t
actually be &amp;#8220;murder&amp;#8221;; it should be &amp;#8220;involuntary manslaughter&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Apple vs. Dell/Microsoft</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft.html</guid>

	<link>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft.html</link>


	<category>apple</category>

	<category>reviews</category>

	<category>usability</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 20:02:15 -0400</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-03T00:02:15Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;27 July 2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a MacBook Air that I used as my work (consulting) computer for 18
months or so. Then my new job gave me a Dell laptop that &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/115702184162942442429/posts/HrRj16gEYJa&quot;&gt;feels seriously
inferior&lt;/a&gt;, but as with all things Windows/Dell, it is sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yesterday I did something I&amp;#8217;ve done hundreds of times before with my Air,
but never before with my Dell: I closed the lid at the end of the day without
shutting things down first, stuffed it in my bag, and went home. (I was in a
hurry.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Air, that reliably sleeps the laptop, and I can always trust that
everything will be exactly as I left it when I reopen the lid, and the battery
won&amp;#8217;t have drained at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew not to trust the same thing on Windows, but I was in a hurry so I
decided to risk it, and maybe if it turned out well I&amp;#8217;d adjust my opinion
about Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did I see when I opened it this morning? A boot-time message telling
me that the laptop had shut itself down because it was overheating, which
usually happens because it is in a tightly enclosed space with the fan vents
blocked. Like, say, a laptop bag. And by &amp;#8220;shut itself down&amp;#8221; they mean &amp;#8220;hard
power off, no saving your work&amp;#8221;. And they mean that they waited until the
battery was half drained to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I checked and I do have the laptop set to sleep when I close the lid. So
it should have just slept, and it shouldn&amp;#8217;t have been generating heat
(although I&amp;#8217;m not certain if the Windows sleep really does go that far), so it
shouldn&amp;#8217;t have had this problem. But it did. I&amp;#8217;m guessing the culprit is
Outlook, which often prevents rebooting because of third-party integrations
that aren&amp;#8217;t very well-done, so maybe it also prevented sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then of course, the culprit is Windows for actually listening to Outlook
and not putting the laptop to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then Dell is really the savior here; faced with Windows not sleeping when
it was supposed to, Dell&amp;#8217;s choice was either to let the laptop overheat (and
break permanently), or build a feature to shut it off when it begins to. So,
thanks, Dell!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than that, thanks to Apple for making devices where I just don&amp;#8217;t have
to worry about crap like this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Comments&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft#c000947&quot;&gt;172 days ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mattmc3.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;mattmc3&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, right? The thought of ever going back just doesn&amp;#8217;t cross my mind. But,
as a counter-point, I did have the exact opposite problem today in fact. I
wanted my laptop to stay on while I updated the maps on my Garmin and the Mac
insisted it follow the energy settings which meant that the Garmin was 1/2
updated when the laptop force ejected it as part of its sleep routine. The
default behavior is certainly what you want 99% of the time, but for that 1% I
wish there was an easy way to say &amp;#8220;delay sleep&amp;#8221; for x minutes because I know
what I&amp;#8217;m doing and after that return to my prior settings automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/624/apple-vs-dell-microsoft#c000948&quot;&gt;172 days ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com&quot;&gt;Nathan Arthur&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://semaja2.net/insomniaxinfo&quot;&gt;InsomniaX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/macosx-nosleep-extension/&quot;&gt;NoSleep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And &lt;a href=&quot;http://lightheadsw.com/caffeine/&quot;&gt;Caffeine&lt;/a&gt; for non-lid-closed cases)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>How I manage my inbox</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/628/how-i-manage-my-inbox.html</guid>

	<link>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/628/how-i-manage-my-inbox.html</link>


	<category>effectiveness</category>

	<category>geek</category>


	<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 20:02:15 -0400</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-06-03T00:02:15Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4 August 2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that other people don&amp;#8217;t use email the same way I do. And it turns
out that some people think my email use patterns might have some useful ideas.
It also happens to be the case that I&amp;#8217;m well-known for being good at keeping
track of things, and my inbox is basically the way I do that, so maybe
explaining my inbox will help people get better at keeping track of things. So
here it is &lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First rule: the only things in the inbox are things that are still underway,
in real life. Once something is done, the email gets deleted, archived, or
filed in a folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second rule: only have a single inbox that receives messages that might result
in a to-do for you. Mail rules that filter email lists and such into folders
is fine - as long as that email list is passive-only. (And in the rare case
where something from the list generates a to-do, move that email to the
inbox.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third rule: the inbox has three statuses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; New / unread - the things that you haven&amp;#8217;t seen yet, or that you need to deal with in the short term (today or tomorrow, ideally). Example: an email from your mother with a question about her TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Flagged / starred - the things that you need to deal with in the longer term (3 days - a few weeks). Example: an email reminding you to blog about your inbox usage rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Read / not-flagged - things where someone else is responsible for taking the next step, but which you want to keep tracking. Example: a shipping notice from Amazon.com, for an item that hasn&amp;#8217;t arrived yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Fourth rule: &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; that I have to keep track of (i.e. my to-do list)
goes into my inbox. I am constantly sending myself little one-line emails,
because that&amp;#8217;s how I manage my to-do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some secondary rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If something sits in the &amp;#8220;flagged / starred&amp;#8221; category long enough, give up and archive/delete/file it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Periodically review the entire inbox, cleaning out things that aren&amp;#8217;t going to get done, and following up on things that have stalled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The entire inbox (all three categories) should always be relatively short. I can gauge how overworked I am by whether my inbox has 5 things in it (ideal!) or 50 (WAY too many). I typically run at about 20. Looking at my (personal) inbox now, I have 6 unread, 8 starred, and 4 read.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some notes about how this works in Outlook / corporate email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use flags for the long-term to-do items, and unread for the &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; status. I&amp;#8217;ve tried setting flag reminder dates, or using different-color flags, and neither adds much value (for me) compared to the time spent managing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I delete most email once it&amp;#8217;s handled, but I don&amp;#8217;t have Outlook remove things from the Deleted folder until it&amp;#8217;s a month old.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I keep all my sent mail. (Have it be locally archived if your company restricts mailbox size on the server.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I keep a few key folders for explicitly filing things - but not many. It&amp;#8217;s easier to search than it is to manually file and then try to guess where I filed something. It&amp;#8217;s also very freeing to just accept that deleting email is OK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I usually have a few project-specific folders under my Inbox, where I stash things I might need to reference later for a specific project. Once the project is done, I delete the folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also keep a single &amp;#8220;Save&amp;#8221; folder that catches most things I think I might want to get back to someday, and then usually I have a few sub-folders for specific topics (like &amp;#8220;sales&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;people&amp;#8221;) - but I keep it to just a few folders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some notes about how this works in Gmail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use Gmail&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://gmailblog.blogspot.com/2010/08/email-overload-try-priority-inbox.html&quot;&gt;priority inbox&lt;/a&gt; because it is designed for me. It effectively (automatically) splits the &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; category into &amp;#8220;email I need to see soon&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;everything else&amp;#8221;, and then gives me a split view of my three categories, so the most urgent stuff is at the top, and the least urgent at the bottom. It&amp;#8217;s perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I archive every email, no matter how unimportant, once I&amp;#8217;m done with it. No sorting or (manual) tagging - search is the answer here. And by archiving everything, I don&amp;#8217;t have to pause and make a decision about whether to archive or delete. Sometimes I&amp;#8217;ll forward an email to myself just to add keywords to it, so I can find it more easily later, but that&amp;#8217;s it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do make use of Gmail&amp;#8217;s automatic filters, to automatically tag emails. Most of that&amp;#8217;s for shopping stuff (like Amazon) so I can spot it easily and mark it read (until the item arrives, when I archive it). Sometimes I&amp;#8217;ll make a manual tag for temporary topic management (like &amp;#8220;holiday planning&amp;#8221;), but that&amp;#8217;s rare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Comments&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/628/how-i-manage-my-inbox#c000949&quot;&gt;164 days ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mattmc3.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;mattmc3&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is fascinating. I know you always ask me to send you an e-mail about
something or other, and have watched you e-mail yourself. I never could figure
that out, because I strongly dislike e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get 100s of e-mails a day. Other than volume, the trouble I have with e-mail
is that search (in Outlook) stinks (s..l..o..w..), and reading messages to
filter through someone&amp;#8217;s prose just to get action items is tedious. I only
want to do it one time and distill the info down to something that can go into
my &amp;#8220;trusted system&amp;#8221; (Paul Allen&amp;#8217;s GTD philopophy). Appigo&amp;#8217;s TODO iOS app is my
current TS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My typical method of dealing with e-mail is to do a simple 4-bucket filter -
either an e-mail is sent directly to me by someone internal to my company,
something is sneeze mailed to me via a distro within my company, something is
sent to me by someone external to my company, or I&amp;#8217;m cc:ed. From there, the
e-mails never leave those 4 &amp;#8220;inboxes&amp;#8221;. I read and respond to direct e-mails
within 24 hours. I usually do not respond to cc:ed e-mails as they are an FYI.
External stuff requires some on-the-fly decision making as to how to handle
it. And I try to just read the sneeze-mail stuff no more than twice a day.
Everything that I guess would take more than 5 minutes goes into TODO (synced
with toodledo.com, so I could input there as well). Anything under 5 minutes,
I get the ball back out of my court. Any e-mail chain longer than 5 messages
requires a meeting, and instead of replying I schedule it right there. I
occasionally need to sort/search an e-mail, but not often. Usually it&amp;#8217;s to
forward something I already sent to prove I sent it to someone less organized.
I try to have no more than 10 todos assigned per day. This has cut way down on
my e-mail management, as there isn&amp;#8217;t any. Filter automatically, and read
different buckets with different urgency. Important items get written in a
separate system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not sure I&amp;#8217;d have any success with your method, but I&amp;#8217;m glad it works for
you. Seems to have stuck with you for a long time, whereas I&amp;#8217;ve had to adapt
mine again and again, but I think I&amp;#8217;ve finally found a working system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/628/how-i-manage-my-inbox#c000950&quot;&gt;159 days ago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com&quot;&gt;Nathan Arthur&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search in Outlook has been very fast for me - I&amp;#8217;m using Outlook 2010, on an
SSD. Maybe the SSD makes a big difference? If I didn&amp;#8217;t have the search, I
probably would have a different approach in Outlook. (Gmail, obviously, rocks
the search.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually avoid &amp;#8220;distilling&amp;#8221; until I&amp;#8217;m ready to actually do the work. Too
often, the requirements change by the time I get around to it &lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt; I just keep
the latest email in the thread (which is a pain in Outlook, but zero work in
Gmail).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve seen &lt;em&gt;David&lt;/em&gt; Allen&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;GTD&amp;#8221; stuff before, and I always thought it involved
too much active management of work items. I don&amp;#8217;t think I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen &lt;em&gt;Paul&lt;/em&gt;
Allen&amp;#8217;s GTD stuff before. Is &lt;a href=&quot;http://drhaswell.com/index.php/2010/05/getting-things-done-book-takeaway/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; a reasonable overview of it? If so,
it&amp;#8217;s almost &lt;strong&gt;exactly&lt;/strong&gt; what I do, just via unread, starred, and folders,
instead of via some external tool. Email &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the tool I use for managing my
to-do list; that&amp;#8217;s why I&amp;#8217;m constantly emailing to-do items to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really don&amp;#8217;t like the idea of moving stuff out of email and into some other
tool - that&amp;#8217;s an extra step you have to take for every to-do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal, external, or CC - those doesn&amp;#8217;t consistently drive meaningful
response patterns for me. I don&amp;#8217;t think it would do much good for me to
separate them out. (I already do separate out email lists.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My system has evolved somewhat over time, but the only major difference was
that I stopped saving all email, a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>


</item>
<item>

	<title>Laptop bag 4.0, backlogs, and story form</title>


	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/622/laptop-bag-40-backlogs-and-story-form.html</guid>

	<link>http://magnetic-babysitter.local/blog/622/laptop-bag-40-backlogs-and-story-form.html</link>


	<category>agile</category>

	<category>business</category>

	<category>effectiveness</category>

	<category>flying</category>

	<category>geek</category>

	<category>product management</category>

	<category>reviews</category>

	<category>travel</category>

	<category>usability</category>


	<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
	<dcterms:modified>2013-08-18T04:53:08Z</dcterms:modified>

	<description>&lt;p&gt;Somewhere out there is a laptop bag just waiting for me to find it.  But first, I have to spec it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randsinrepose.com/&quot;&gt;Rands&lt;/a&gt;, I recently got &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.randsinrepose.com/archives/2011/12/04/a_bag_of_holding.html&quot;&gt;laptop bag religion&lt;/a&gt; and I spent an excessive amount of time cogitating about features, price, tradeoffs, where to buy, and features again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got serious about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;#39;t yet found the bag, but in the meantime, I&amp;#39;ve written this blog post, because it provided the excuse I needed to really &lt;del&gt;go batshit insane&lt;/del&gt; do a thorough job of my analysis.  Not only does this post include a detailed list of requirements for my perfect laptop bag, but it also includes a glance into what I do in my life as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rainskit.com/blog/586/what-i-do&quot;&gt;Product Manager&lt;/a&gt;.  Hopefully one or the other of those is interesting enough to keep your attention &lt;img src=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/./smileys/smile.png&quot; alt=&quot;:)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magnetic-babysitter.local/./blog/622/laptop-bag-40-backlogs-and-story-form.html#more&quot;&gt;Read more&amp;#8230;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>


</item>

</channel>
</rss>
